[
    {
        "question": "Which manufacturer unveiled the BD475-2 Dozer, India's biggest and most advanced crawler dozer?",
        "options": [
            "BEML",
            "Larsen & Toubro",
            "BHEL",
            "Mahindra",
            "BEL"
        ],
        "answer": "BEML"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state has the Ratapani Tiger Reserve, India's 57th tiger reserve, been notified, 17 years after its approval by the National Tiger Conservation Authority?",
        "options": [
            "Maharashtra",
            "Rajasthan",
            "Madhya Pradesh",
            "Chhattisgarh",
            "Kerala"
        ],
        "answer": "Madhya Pradesh"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many Sewer and Septic Tank Workers (SSWs) have been identified under the NAMASTE scheme by December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "57758",
            "13604",
            "24574",
            "41800",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "57758"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country successfully tested the Long-Range Hypersonic Weapon (LRHW) in 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Russia",
            "China",
            "United States",
            "India",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "United States"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chief Financial Officer (CFO) of Oil India Limited (OIL)? (December 2024)",
        "options": [
            "Rupam Barua",
            "Ramesh Kumar",
            "Trailukya Borgohain",
            "Abhijit Majumder",
            "Tabish Seher"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "SLINEX (Sri Lanka-India Exercise) was recently conducted in December 2024. When was it first held?",
        "options": [
            "2002",
            "2005",
            "2012",
            "2015",
            "2019"
        ],
        "answer": "2005"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the total outlay approved by the Ministry of Tourism for 40 projects under the Special Assistance to States/Union Territories for Capital Investment (SASCI) guidelines?",
        "options": [
            "Rs 3,100 crore",
            "Rs 3,295 crore",
            "Rs 3,560 crore",
            "Rs 2,952 crore",
            "Rs 3,750 crore"
        ],
        "answer": "Rs 3,295 crore"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which actor featured in the new brand campaign of Canara HSBC Life Insurance?",
        "options": [
            "Akshay Kumar",
            "Ranveer Singh",
            "Shah Rukh Khan",
            "Varun Sharma",
            "Ranbir Kapoor"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has recently been appointed as the Chief Vigilance Officer (CVO) of Bharat Electronics Limited (BEL)?",
        "options": [
            "Anil Kumar Gupta",
            "Suresh Chandra",
            "Ramesh Kumar Singh",
            "Nilabhra Sengupta",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Nilabhra Sengupta"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the book launched by Dr. Dinesh Shahra that is based on Dalai Lama's teachings on happiness, well-being, and spiritual growth?",
        "options": [
            "The Art of Happiness",
            "The Dalai Lama's Teachings",
            "Inner Peace and Compassion",
            "Dalai Lama's Secret to Happiness",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has been awarded the hosting rights for the ISSF Junior Shooting World Cup 2025?",
        "options": [
            "China",
            "Germany",
            "India",
            "South Korea",
            "Italy"
        ],
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which village in Gujarat has become India's first solar border village?",
        "options": [
            "Masali Village",
            "Vav Village",
            "Suigam Village",
            "Banaskantha Village",
            "Bela Village"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which English news channel won the 'Best News Channel (English)' award at the ITA Awards 2024?",
        "options": [
            "NDTV",
            "Republic TV",
            "India Today",
            "CNN-News18",
            "Times Now"
        ],
        "answer": "India Today"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct regarding the Kisan Kavach anti-pesticide bodysuit launched by Dr. Jitendra Singh?",
        "options": [
            "It is a reusable bodysuit priced at â‚¹6,000.",
            "It was developed by BRIC-inStem in collaboration with Sepio Health Pvt. Ltd.",
            "The bodysuit uses advanced nanotechnology to neutralize pesticides.",
            "The bodysuit was distributed to all Indian farmers for free at the launch event.",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many total medals did the Indian team win at the Asian Youth and Junior Weightlifting Championships 2024 and where did it take place?",
        "options": [
            "33 medals, Doha",
            "42 medals, Abu Dhabi",
            "50 medals, Melbourne",
            "25 medals, Baku",
            "11 medals, Durban"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who became the first Indian to win an FIA Formula 2 Constructors' World Championship, achieving five podiums and claiming India's first F2 pole position in 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Arjun Maini",
            "Jehan Daruvala",
            "Narain Karthikeyan",
            "Kush Maini",
            "Pankaj Advani"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been named TIME's 2024 Person of the Year?",
        "options": [
            "Donald Trump",
            "Elon Musk",
            "Volodymyr Zelenskyy",
            "Vladimir Putin",
            "Malala Yousufzhai"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "India has set up its first diabetes biobank in Chennai. Which two organizations collaborated to set up India's first diabetes biobank?",
        "options": [
            "Indian Council of Medical Research and Madras Diabetes Research Foundation",
            "All India Institute of Medical Sciences and Tata Trusts",
            "World Health Organization and All India Institute of Medical Sciences",
            "Indian Medical Association and National Institute of Diabetes",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Indian Council of Medical Research and Madras Diabetes Research Foundation"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the primary objective of the 'Track and Trace Mechanism' approved by the GST Council in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "To monitor imports and exports",
            "To monitor GST rate expansion on certain goods",
            "To simplify GST registration process and to track the GSTIN holder locations",
            "To curb tax evasion in specified commodities",
            "To impose tax at every level"
        ],
        "answer": "To curb tax evasion in specified commodities"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country recently unveiled the CR450 prototype, the world's fastest high-speed train?",
        "options": [
            "Japan",
            "Germany",
            "China",
            "South Korea",
            "Italy"
        ],
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization has partnered with boAt to mentor and support startups in the D2C and manufacturing sectors?",
        "options": [
            "NITI Aayog",
            "Department for Promotion of Industry and Internal Trade (DPIIT)",
            "Ministry of Micro, Small and Medium Enterprises (MSME)",
            "Startup India",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country's astronauts broke NASA's spacewalk record by completing a 9-hour EVA outside the Tiangong space station?",
        "options": [
            "China",
            "USA",
            "Japan",
            "Russia",
            "India"
        ],
        "answer": "China"
    },
    {
        "question": "With which bank has Department for Promotion of Industry and Internal Trade (DPIIT) signed an MoU to empower startups and foster innovation?",
        "options": [
            "ICICI Bank",
            "HDFC Bank",
            "State Bank of India",
            "Axis Bank",
            "PNB"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city is the FIFAe World Cup 2024, featuring eFootball, scheduled to be held?",
        "options": [
            "London",
            "Tokyo",
            "Riyadh",
            "Seoul",
            "Paris"
        ],
        "answer": "Riyadh"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which military exercise is being held in Nepal with participation from India and Nepal armies in December 2024-January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Exercise SHAKTI",
            "Exercise MAITREE",
            "Exercise SURYA KIRAN",
            "Exercise SAMPREETI",
            "Exercise TARANG"
        ],
        "answer": "Exercise SURYA KIRAN"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country contributed the highest Foreign Direct Investment (FDI) into India during July-September 2024, accounting for 50% of the total inflows?",
        "options": [
            "United States",
            "Singapore",
            "United Kingdom",
            "Japan",
            "Canada"
        ],
        "answer": "Singapore"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization launched the Tiara Credit Card for women?",
        "options": [
            "State Bank of India",
            "BOBCARD Limited",
            "HDFC Bank",
            "ICICI Bank",
            "PNB"
        ],
        "answer": "BOBCARD Limited"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the nationwide campaign that was launched during the 4th Good Governance Week on 19th December, 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Prashasan Gaon Ki Baat",
            "Prashasan Gaon Ki Yatra",
            "Prashasan Gaon Ki Abhiyan",
            "Prashasan Gaon Ki Ore",
            "Prashasan Gaon Ki Tarakki"
        ],
        "answer": "Prashasan Gaon Ki Ore"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nat Sciver-Brunt has recently smashed fastest women's test century. Who held the previous record for the fastest Women's Test hundred before Nat Sciver-Brunt?",
        "options": [
            "Shafali Verma",
            "Chamani Seneviratna",
            "Smriti Mandhana",
            "Maia Bouchier",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Chamani Seneviratna"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the record net worth achieved by Elon Musk, as per the Bloomberg Billionaires Index?",
        "options": [
            "$400 billion",
            "$450 billion",
            "$500 billion",
            "$550 billion",
            "$600 billion"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which scheme did the government provide grants of â‚¹50 lakh each to two start-ups focusing on sustainable and medical textiles?",
        "options": [
            "Atal Innovation Mission",
            "GREAT scheme",
            "Start-Up India Initiative",
            "Technical Textiles Grant Program",
            "MGNREGA"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has become Africa's largest investor, with Emirati companies announcing $110 billion in projects between 2019 and 2023, including $72 billion in renewable energy?",
        "options": [
            "Qatar",
            "United States",
            "United Arab Emirates",
            "China",
            "Bahrain"
        ],
        "answer": "United Arab Emirates"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the primary aim of the European Space Agency's (ESA) Proba-3 mission, which will be launched by ISRO via PSLV-C59?",
        "options": [
            "To study Earth's atmospheric changes",
            "To explore the Sun's corona",
            "To monitor asteroids near Earth",
            "To test satellite communication technologies",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "To explore the Sun's corona"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the seventh Missile Cum Ammunition Barge (LSAM 14) launched?",
        "options": [
            "Visakhapatnam",
            "Kochi",
            "Pune",
            "Mira Bhayandar",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Mira Bhayandar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which edition of the Raising Day Parade of the BSF was celebrated in Jodhpur, Rajasthan on 8th December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "50th",
            "55th",
            "60th",
            "65th",
            "69th"
        ],
        "answer": "60th"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has secured seven key positions in the interim organizational structure of the new Asian body formed by World Boxing, including a board member role for its Boxing Federation President?",
        "options": [
            "China",
            "Japan",
            "South Korea",
            "India",
            "Laos"
        ],
        "answer": "India"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the theme of the 4th National Conference of Chief Secretaries held in New Delhi?",
        "options": [
            "Enhancing Infrastructure for Sustainable Growth",
            "Promoting Entrepreneurship, Employment, and Skilling",
            "Strengthening Health and Education Systems",
            "Digital Transformation for National Development",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which UN organization has recognized six environmental leaders with the 2024 Champions of the Earth award for their efforts in tackling land degradation, drought, and desertification?",
        "options": [
            "UN Environment Program (UNEP)",
            "United Nations Development Program (UNDP)",
            "United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO)",
            "United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC)",
            "WWF"
        ],
        "answer": "UN Environment Program (UNEP)"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much loan did the World Bank approve for Amaravati's Integrated Urban Development Program?",
        "options": [
            "$500 million",
            "$600 million",
            "$800 million",
            "$900 million",
            "$1000 million"
        ],
        "answer": "$800 million"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian state declared the Maha Kumbh Mela area as a new district in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Madhya Pradesh",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Bihar",
            "Rajasthan",
            "Gujarat"
        ],
        "answer": "Uttar Pradesh"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where has the Indian Army launched its Artificial Intelligence Incubation Centre (IAAIIC)?",
        "options": [
            "Delhi",
            "Pune",
            "Bengaluru",
            "Chandigarh",
            "Chennai"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the 11th Men's Hockey Junior Asia Cup 2024 final, which team did India defeat to win the title?",
        "options": [
            "Japan",
            "South Korea",
            "Malaysia",
            "Pakistan",
            "Oman"
        ],
        "answer": "Pakistan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is Mayotte, which was severely impacted by Cyclone Chido?",
        "options": [
            "Indian Ocean, a French overseas department",
            "Pacific Ocean, an autonomous region of France",
            "Atlantic Ocean, a territory of Spain",
            "Arabian Sea, an island nation",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Indian Ocean, a French overseas department"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian bowler recently equaled the record ICC rating of 904 in Men's Test Bowling Rankings in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Ravichandran Ashwin",
            "Anil Kumble",
            "Jasprit Bumrah",
            "Mohammed Shami",
            "Harshit Rana"
        ],
        "answer": "Jasprit Bumrah"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian Grandmaster recently advanced to the quarterfinals of the World Blitz Championship with a score of 9.5 out of 11 games?",
        "options": [
            "R Praggnanandhaa",
            "R Vaishali",
            "Arjun Erigaisi",
            "Koneru Humpy",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who secured three gold medals in women's air pistol at the 67th National Shooting Championship?",
        "options": [
            "Rhythm Sangwan",
            "Palak",
            "Suruchi",
            "Manu Bhaker",
            "Prajakta Priyam"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which mechanism was established between India and Kuwait in December, 2024 to enhance bilateral cooperation?",
        "options": [
            "Joint Trade Commission",
            "Joint Commission for Cooperation",
            "Strategic Partnership Council",
            "Economic Collaboration Council",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "Joint Commission for Cooperation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which activity was excluded from the 18th Chitwan Elephant and Tourism Festival due to animal rights concerns?",
        "options": [
            "Elephant beauty contest",
            "Elephant football matches",
            "Elephant polo",
            "Elephant parades",
            "Elephant march"
        ],
        "answer": "Elephant polo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who clinched their first national title in the men's 25m rapid-fire pistol event at the 67th National Shooting Championship Competitions?",
        "options": [
            "Gurpreet Singh",
            "Vijayveer Sidhu",
            "Shivam Shukla",
            "Ankur Goel",
            "Premjeet Dhillon"
        ],
        "answer": "Vijayveer Sidhu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is set to launch a free mRNA cancer vaccine in 2025?",
        "options": [
            "United States",
            "Russia",
            "Germany",
            "China",
            "UK"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    }
]